"Touo University Student Murder Case.
“東央大學生殺人案
A student in Touo University's Science and Engineering Department
東央大學理工學部在籍生
murdered his girlfriend, a student in the Literature Department.
殺害了交往中的文學部女學生
He was arrested and charged by Yokohama Public Prosecutors' Office.
逮捕後由橫濱地檢起訴
The prosecutor in charge was Shin Kurokawa."
負責檢察官為黑川真”
That case from back then still bothers you?
你還拘泥於那時的事啊？
You haven't changed at all.
你也還是老樣子啊
"The defense lawyer was Hoshundo Law Office's lawyer,
“辯護人是保駿堂法律事務所的
Hideharu Beppu."
別府秀治律師”
He was Mr. Beppu's elder brother.
別府所長的哥哥
He received much criticism from the public,
受到了輿論嚴厲的批判
and he passed away because of that.
他因此積鬱成病，撒手人寰
VICTIM, AYAKA AKIU
（受害者，秋保彩花小姐）
Involved?
相關人士？
Our positions were different,
雖然立場不同 卻都經歷了相同的痛苦回憶
"The prisoner committed suicide after he was found guilty."
“判決有罪後，受刑人自殺身亡”
Ask Kurokawa if you are curious.
那麼在意就直接問本人啊
Kurokawa, see you tomorrow.
黑川，明天見了
-See you.
-辛苦了
Ms. Wakura, will you come with me after work?
和倉律師 下班後要不要跟我聚一聚？
You've been absorbed in reading the file, right?
你一直在讀那份檔案吧？
You look like you desperately want to talk to someone about it.
看你一臉想找人談的樣子
But Ms. Kinosaki, your son…
但是城崎小姐，你的孩子…
So we'll go to my home.
所以就約家裡，我還得去接孩子下課
Please do the shopping.
麻煩你幫忙買東西了
Yes?
誰啊？
-I'm Wakura. -Come in!
-我是和倉 -進來吧
HONOKA AND HARUTO
（穗香與晴斗）
Hello. I'm here.
打擾了
Oh, good evening.
-辛苦了，快進來吧 -是
Look, Haruto,
來，晴斗
meet Ms. Wakura. I just told you about her.
這位就是剛才媽媽說的和倉律師
Nice to meet you. I'm Kaede Wakura.
初次見面，我叫和倉楓
Haruto, four years old.
我叫晴斗，今年四歲
HARUTO KINOSAKI, HONOKA'S SON
（城崎晴斗，穗香的兒子）
My son is always like this in front of ladies he likes.
這孩子看到喜歡的女生類型 就會變這樣
He is adorable.
好可愛
But I'm telling you, if you toy with my Haruto,
醜話說在前，敢玩弄我家晴斗
I won't forgive you.
我可不會放過你
Toy with him?
玩弄？
Thanks.
謝謝
Wow, you love to read? I'm surprised.
城崎小姐意外地愛讀書啊
"Surprised"? How rude of you.
你這說法未免太失禮了
Well, I read all of them because I had to.
不過那些書 都是有需要才逼著自己讀的
You had to?
有需要才逼著自己讀的？
My parents succumbed to a disease when I was in college.
念大學時，我父母生病倒下
I needed money, so I started to work as a hostess.
因為需要錢，我開始做酒店小姐
PSYCHOLOGY, CRIMINAL PSYCHOLOGY
（《心理學》）
Then I worked as a manga artist's assistant
那之後我又成為漫畫家助手
and was in charge of managing expenses.
被交付了管理經費的工作
It made me want to be a tax accountant.
而開始準備考稅務師執照
Then I married the eldest son of a farm owner
接著又跟那時交往的農家長男結婚
and took over the family business.
一起繼承農田
When I gave birth to Haruto,
生下晴斗不久發現老公外遇
I asked Hoshundo Law Office
在打監護權官司時
They said they had a vacancy for a clerk,
接著事務所告訴我他們有行政職缺
so I started working there.
最終我才會在保駿堂工作
Wow, there have been so many ups and downs in your life.
你的人生也太曲折了吧
Well, everyone has their own past.
這個嘛，人都有過去嘛
In some cases, they don't want others to mention it.
有時候也會有不想被碰觸的過去
-Mommy, I'm hungry. -Okay.
-媽媽，我肚子餓了 -馬上好
I will tidy up the place later.
待會我再來整理吧
We haven't talked about today's main topic.
畢竟都還沒切入今天的正題
Honestly, reading the file only made me confused.
老實說，看了那些檔案 我也只是更混亂而已
But the content is simple, right?
內容很簡單吧？
The victim of that murder in the past was Dr. Akiu's younger sister.
過去發生的殺人案 受害者是秋保教授的妹妹
Mr. Kurokawa's father and Mr. Yufuin's partner,
負責官司的是黑川律師的父親 跟湯布院律師的搭檔
Yeah, that's true, but…
是這樣沒錯啦
The prisoner killed himself after he was found guilty.
判決有罪後，受刑人自殺
But he could have been wrongly convicted,
但也可能是冤罪 所以大家都難以釋懷
I know Mr. Kurokawa's father was the prosecutor,
但就算父親 就是當時那起案件的檢察官
but isn't it weird that Mr. Kurokawa insists
黑川律師對冤罪的執著 也還是太反常了
And Dr. Akiu's sister was the victim,
身為受害者遺屬 秋保教授的協助也是…
I don't know what Dr. Akiu really thinks.
我不明白秋保教授真正的用意
We can't be thoughtless in questioning him either.
這也不是可以隨便問的
But the reason that Mr. Kurokawa insists on doing this…
但黑川律師會這麼執著，有其他原因
What is the other reason?
什麼其他原因？
This is ridiculous!
別開玩笑了
-Coffee. -Thank you.
-咖啡 -謝謝
His dad is famous. No wonder there are so many reporters.
聚集這麼多人啊 真不愧是大人物的兒子
-Someone's coming out. -Okay.
-人出來了 -是
Hey. Why are you taking photos, jerks?
喂，你們拍什麼拍啊？
Hey! Who is letting you take photos?
喂，誰說你們可以拍的？
Don't pull me!
別拉我
YUYA TARUMAE SELF-DESCRIBED MUSICIAN
（樽前裕也，自稱音樂人）
Hey, I didn't do anything!
我什麼也沒做喔
Let's go.
走了
-Okay. -Hurry up.
-是 -動作快
Hello.
你好
YOSHINOBU USUTA, TARUMAE'S HOUSEKEEPER
（有珠田義信，樽前家傭人）
Good morning.
早安
I told you I don't know him at all!
就說了我根本不認識他啊
We did different subjects and we've never met!
我們隸屬不同學院，也沒見過面
Universities for rich boys are good for nothing.
專收有錢少爺的大學沒一個好 至少這是正當見解
-What's going on? -You are good for nothing too!
-怎麼了？ -你也沒什麼好的嘛
The suspect of the fatal shooting in Shinagawa two months ago
兩個月前品川區發生的槍殺案 嫌疑人今早被逮捕了
He's the son of the owner of a big company,
而他居然是 樽前物產這間大公司的少爺
and he graduated from Keishin University, like Isawa.
似乎跟石和一樣是啟進大學畢業生
Ms. Wakura, listen to me. Mr. Noboribetsu is horrible!
和倉律師，請聽我說 登別律師很過分耶
See? You rely on other people right away.
看吧，像這樣馬上搬救兵 就是你沒用的地方了
Sorry, I'm not interested.
抱歉，我沒興趣
THE TOUO UNIVERSITY STUDENT MURDER CASE
（東央大學生殺人案）
Kaede!
小楓
What? Haruto?
什麼？晴斗？
Come on, Haru. You shouldn't do that.
真是的，晴斗，不能這樣啊
I'm sorry, I looked away for a bit.
不好意思，是我沒顧好
What is going on here?
這是什麼狀況？
He got a fever this morning and took the day off nursery school.
他今天早上有點發燒 我就沒讓他去托兒所，然後…
I'm here because I miss you, Kaede!
我想來見你，小楓
Yes?
什麼？
I just heard.
我剛才聽他說了
Haru fell in love with you when he saw you yesterday
小晴他昨天對你一見鍾情
and he wants to marry you.
似乎想跟你結婚呢
He proposed to me in the morning?
一早就被求婚？
But you have to start from being friends with her.
這種事要先從朋友做起才行
-Friends? -Yes.
-朋友？ -對
Use your cuteness to make a rigid girl fall in love with you.
防備心看起來比較強的女生呢…
All right, then.
好，我明白了，那麼我會讓黑川負責
Okay. Goodbye.
是，失陪了
Blimey!
真是的
Sorry for the trouble.
真抱歉，給你添麻煩了
It's no trouble at all. There you go.
一點也不麻煩，請用
-Get well soon, Haru. -Okay.
要快點好起來喔，小晴
Kurokawa and Ms. Wakura, come with me.
黑川，還有和倉律師也來一下
I just got a call and it was a request for criminal defense.
我剛才接到電話，是刑事辯護委託
Yes? You accepted a request for criminal defense?
什麼？是所長您 接下這個刑事辯護案的嗎？
It was made by the CEO of one of our client companies.
是跟我們有顧問契約的 企業社長親自拜託的
Cases you were in charge of were reported in the news lately, right?
最近你經手的案件 都受到媒體大肆報導對吧？
He wants you to prove his son's innocence and I couldn't say no.
他希望你能幫他兒子洗清冤屈 我實在無法拒絕
What case is it?
是什麼案子？
It's the fatal shooting in Shinagawa.
是發生在品川區的槍殺案
It's your job to make me innocent, idiot.
找出證人不就是你的工作嗎？
I will investigate thoroughly and defend you.
我會徹底調查，奮戰到底
Is it true Haru was kidnapped?
小晴真的被綁架了嗎？
-Hey… -Haruto! Where are you?
-晴斗 -在案件中失去家人的痛苦
Can you hear my voice?
聽得到我的聲音嗎？
This is what he is!
他就是這種人！
Defendant!
被告
KEEP OUT
（禁止進入）
The incident happened on December 19, 2018.
事發於平成30年12月19日
In an empty warehouse in Shinagawa owned by Tarumae Property Agency,
樽前物產品川區廢棄倉庫中
the body of someone shot dead by a gun was found.
發現一具遭槍殺的遺體
From his belongings,
以持有物品確認死者身分為 都內的飛特族，新島彰，26歲
The estimated time of death was between two to three p.m. on the same day.
推測死亡時間為 當天下午兩點至三點之間
The police thinks the suspect was Yuya Tarumae,
警方將嫌疑人 鎖定在死者大學時的友人
Akira's university friend
也就是樽前物產社長的獨生子
and the only son of Tarumae Property Agency's CEO.
樽前裕也進行搜查
In the suspect's bedroom,
並從該嫌疑人自家室內
a lethal weapon, an illegally modified airgun, was found.
找到了具殺傷力的違法改造空氣槍
You currently deny the charges, am I right?
所以你否認自己有嫌疑是嗎？
Of course, because I didn't kill him.
當然了，又不是我做的
But the modified airgun--
但是警方找到的改造空氣槍…
Hey, go on a date with me.
我說啊，你下次跟我約會吧
You are exactly my type.
我超喜歡你這一型的
Another man just proposed to me the other day.
我前幾天才被其他男性求婚而已
Anyway, regarding this case--
比起這個，關於這起案件…
I told you.
就說了
I have no reason to kill Akira.
我沒有理由殺死阿彰啊
Where were you on the 19th of December, when the murder happened?
案發的12月19日 請問你人在哪裡？
I was in my room the whole day.
我一整天都待在房間裡
I had been drinking, sleeping on and off.
一邊喝酒，睡睡醒醒
Oh, and that too.
對了，還有
I had an urge to write something.
我久違地有了創作慾
Write something?
創作慾？
I'm a musician.
我可是個音樂人呢
Around two to three p.m., when Akira was killed,
阿彰被殺死的下午兩點到三點
I'm sure that I was playing the bass in my room.
我很肯定自己在房裡彈貝斯
Is there anybody who can prove that?
有人能幫你作證嗎？
Isn't it your job to find that "someone"?
找出證人不就是你的工作嗎？
My dad told me.
我聽老爸說了
You can prove any bad guy innocent by saying it's a false charge
聽說無論是什麼壞蛋
and you're a skillful lawyer.
你都能辯護到無罪釋放
I doubt it.
這還很難說
Someone innocent is arrested here…
你眼前就有一個被冤枉的人
so just solve the problem quickly.
快點解決吧
Mr. Tarumae, I'll ask you one last time.
樽前先生，我問最後一次
Did you really not kill Akira Niijima?
你真的沒殺害新島彰先生嗎？
I already told you that I didn't kill him.
不是早就說我沒殺了嗎？
Well, even if I had killed him,
不過，就算真的是我殺的
it's your job to make me innocent, idiot.
你的工作也是讓我無罪釋放，笨蛋
-You-- -All right, then.
-我說你… -我明白了
I will investigate thoroughly and defend you.
我會徹底調查，奮戰到底
Excuse me.
打擾了
This is Mr. Yuya's bedroom.
這就是裕也少爺的房間
Wow, it's the Mason model!
這是梅森款的呢
It costs about 500,000 yen, right?
這把應該要五十萬圓左右吧？
I'd like to ask something about the day of the murder.
我想請問案發當天的事
Were you here on that day too?
那天有珠田先生你也在嗎？
Yes, I'm a live-in housekeeper.
是，我是居家傭人
Between two to three p.m., when Niijima was murdered,
下午兩點至三點左右的推測犯案時間
did you see Mr. Yuya?
你有看到裕也先生嗎？
No, Mr. Yuya shut himself in his room the whole day.
不，裕也少爺一直關在房間裡
But was the sound of his bass noisy?
但是貝斯的聲音應該很吵吧？
The room doesn't seem to be soundproof.
這個房間似乎沒有做隔音設施
I think it must be pretty loud.
聲音應該挺大的吧
Yes, we get complaints from the neighbors from time to time.
是，鄰居有時也會抱怨
We asked to talk to President Tarumae as well.
我們事前也有傳達過 想問問樽前社長一些狀況
President Tarumae is busy because of this case.
社長正忙著應對這起案件引發的騷動
He told me to be in charge of this.
他說全權交給我處理
I will go make you some tea.
那個…我先去泡個茶
Maybe even his father has given up on him.
或許連父母都放棄他了吧
Yes, maybe.
或許喔
I asked my college friends about Tarumae.
我也跟大學同窗打聽過他的情報了
They said he had caused problems back then too.
他當時似乎也引發了不少問題
-Problems? -It's a rumor,
-問題？ -只是傳聞
but he assaulted many girls in the club he joined.
不過聽說他曾在活動社團 性侵不只一名女孩
You are the mother of the victim, Akira Niijima?
您是受害者新島彰先生的母親？
Yes.
是的
I heard that your firm's lawyer is the case's defense lawyer.
我聽說是貴事務所的律師負責辯護
Here you go.
請用茶
So, how can we help you?
請問您是為什麼而來呢？
Please do not defend Yuya Tarumae.
我想請貴事務所不要幫樽前裕也辯護
There's no doubt that that guy murdered my son.
我兒子肯定是被他殺死的
Do you have any proof?
您這麼說有什麼依據嗎？
My son had been hanging out and causing trouble
我兒子從大學時代就跟樽前混在一起
with Tarumae since they were in college.
總是在搞些壞事
It seems that he had been using this to demand money from Tarumae.
他似乎還因此跟樽前要錢
Tarumae's father covered this up, so it won't cause any stir.
最後是樽前的爸爸 把事壓下來，所以才沒鬧大
"Sexual assault"?
性侵？
He used this to blackmail Tarumae,
由於令郎用這件事勒索樽前
so Tarumae killed him for revenge?
才遭報復而被射殺嗎？
But according to what you said,
但若照您剛才的說法
your son was his accomplice.
令郎也會變成共犯的
In that case, he couldn't blackmail Tarumae--
那種情況下，勒索應該無法成立…
It's true that it caused trouble, and no doubt Tarumae killed my son!
但確實是有糾紛
Is it necessary to defend that murderer?
為什麼還要幫那種殺人犯辯護？
We're back.
我們回來了
Mr. Kurokawa.
黑川律師
A visitor?
有客人嗎？
She is this case's…
這位是這次案件的…
Welcome back, Taku!
小拓，歡迎回來
Oh, Haru, I'm back.
小晴，我回來了
Haru, we are working now.
小晴，大人在工作喔
The boy is adorable.
好可愛的孩子
How old is he?
幾歲了？
Haruto Kinosaki, four years old.
我叫城崎晴斗，今年四歲
Yeah?
這樣啊
Sorry for coming without an appointment. I'll go now.
抱歉突然來叨擾，今天就先這樣吧
Taku, play with me!
小拓，陪我玩
Okay, let's play. What should we do?
好啊，你想玩什麼呢？
Sorry…
不好意思
October 2. The idiot is making noise today too.
10月2日，那個混蛋今天也一樣吵
As I thought, it is pretty loud.
果然聽得滿清楚的啊
But all the neighbors said
不過案發當天 附近鄰居都說沒聽到貝斯聲
The housekeeper, Mr. Usuta, said he heard it.
居家傭人有珠田先生說有聽到 看來果然是說謊啊
Anyway, the guy's reputation is horrible.
話說回來，這傢伙的評價真是爛透了
Not only does he make noises
不只噪音擾鄰的事
but someone even saw him shooting animals with his airgun.
還有人目擊他用空氣槍射擊動物呢
He abuses animals?
還虐待動物？
His mother died when he was in middle school
他母親在他讀國中時就過世了
and his father has been ignoring him as well.
父親也幾乎放著他不管
I'm not surprised that he became a delinquent.
在這環境下變壞也不奇怪就是了
He's free to be a delinquent,
要變壞就隨他去
but that's not an excuse to kill someone.
但這可不能當犯案藉口啊
And what he did in university too.
而且他在大學時代的事也是
You mean what he did in the club?
活動社團的事嗎？
I've heard something here and there.
我也略知一二
The victim's mother said that it was the motive to kill the victim.
受害者的母親 還說那起案件就是殺人動機呢
You met the victim's mother?
你們見到受害者的母親了？
She came to our office.
她有來我們事務所
I see.
這樣啊
She totally refused to be interviewed by the press.
他們完全不接受媒體採訪呢
She said they had nothing to do with the case.
說他們跟這起案子無關
-Hello.
-午安
Hello, Yuki.
祐樹，午安
Has Haruto recovered from his cold?
晴斗的感冒好了嗎？
Yeah, he's too energetic now. Right?
好了，現在精神好過頭了 反而傷腦筋呢，對吧？
I'll race you there!
我們來賽跑吧
Do you know the supermarket there holds a bargain sale today?
你知道對面超市今天大減價嗎？
-I had no idea. -The eggs are cheap.
-我不知道呢 -雞蛋很便宜喔
Wait, I just bought some yesterday.
我昨天才剛買了啊
COURTHOUSE
（法院）
The first hearing will be three days later. Is that okay?
第一次公判 就在三天後進行，沒問題吧？
-Yes. -All right.
-是 -沒問題
FIRST WITNESS, YOSHINOBU USUTA
（第一人證，有珠田義信）
Mr. Kurokawa.
黑川律師
Yes?
是
I had no idea that you were going to prove that he wasn't the murderer.
沒想到你這次還要著眼爭論犯案嫌疑
And your witness is the suspect's housekeeper?
而且居然找來被告自宅傭人來當證人
What do you mean?
什麼意思？
That man, Usuta,
那個姓有珠田的男人 雖然堅稱案發當天自己在家
but he actually went out.
實際上並非如此
The suspect told him to do some shopping.
被告要他去買東西
When he returned by taxi with items he bought from many shops,
他提著大包小包搭計程車回去
he was seen by the neighbors.
都被鄰居看到了
He went out around one to four p.m.
他是下午一點到四點間出門的
In other words, there was enough time
也就是說 被告有充足時間能出門犯案
It's safer to plead extenuating circumstances instead.
我想你把辯護方針 轉為酌量減刑會比較好吧
I have to respect my client's will
我們必須尊重被告的意志
and I haven't found out everything yet.
事情也還沒全部查明
Excuse me.
失陪了
Mr. Kurokawa.
黑川律師
This case wasn't an accident caused by natural phenomena
這起案件 既不是自然現象造成的偶發事故
and it wasn't suicide.
也不是自殺
It obviously was a murder.
是殺人案件 這是不爭的事實，絕對有犯人
Looking at the evidence,
從證據看來 很明顯就是樽前裕也做的
Yet, do you still think that claiming his innocence is justice?
即使如此你還堅持主張無罪 你認為這就是正義？
I do not defend for the suspect or justice.
我的辯護既不是為了被告 也不是為了正義
I only want to know the truth.
而是為了真相
I'll check everything I can
我會盡全力調查到最後
to judge whether it really is the truth of the case or not.
確認事件的真相
The way you think is dangerous.
這種想法太冒險了
Excuse me.
失陪了
Oh, I have to go now.
那我差不多該走了
Haru!
小晴
Yuki, where is Haruto?
祐樹，晴斗呢？
I don't know.
不知道
Haru!
小晴
Haruto!
晴斗
Where are you?
你在哪裡？
Is it true Haru was kidnapped?
小晴真的被綁架了嗎？
Someone sent a threatening letter?
聽說收到威脅信了？
We just received it.
剛才才收到的
"If the man who deserves punishment isn't punished,
“罪人若沒受到制裁
the boy will die."
小孩必死無疑”
Oh no.
怎麼會這樣？
I just called the police.
剛才已經報警了
But why is Kinosaki's son kidnapped because of this case?
但這起案件 怎麼會把城崎的孩子牽扯進去？
Could it be…
難不成…
What's the matter?
怎麼了？
The address of the victim, Akira Niijima!
我要查受害者新島彰的住址
His mother came here to tell us not to defend Tarumae.
他母親有來事務所要求我們拒絕辯護
Haru was at the office.
當時小晴也在事務所
Please let me check inside!
總之請讓我進去確認一下
Cut it out! Or I'll call the police!
你再不收斂點，我就要報警了
Haruto!
晴斗
Ms. Kinosaki? Please calm down.
您是城崎小姐吧？請冷靜一下
We're from Toshima Police Station. We'd like to talk to you.
我們是豐島警察署的警察 請讓我們進去看一下
What the heck?
這到底是怎樣啊？
Haruto!
-晴斗… -等等…
My wife has been lying in bed since our son was killed.
我老婆自從兒子被殺之後 就臥床不起，請你別鬧了
No doubt my son was killed by that guy.
我兒子肯定是被他殺死的
Who is it?
您是哪位？
It isn't her.
不對
THE BOY WILL DIE
（小孩必死無疑）
Who'd have thought that it was someone else?
沒想到居然另有其人
It's the second email sent by the kidnapper.
這是對方寄來的第二封信
I WON'T ALLOW KUROKAWA TO DEFEND ANYONE
（禁止黑川律師辯護）
THE BOY WILL DIE IF YOU DISOBEY ME
（否則小孩必死無疑）
The police said that it could also be harassment
警方說犯人的目的
towards Kurokawa himself.
也有可能是衝著黑川而來
What should we do about the defense?
辯護要怎麼處理呢？
What else can we do? We have to drop the case.
這還用問？只能退出了
Exactly. Even if we defend Tarumae, the chance we'll win is very small.
就是說啊 而且就算辯護也幾乎沒有勝算
That's true. I'll tell Mr. Tarumae that we'll drop the case.
也對，我去跟樽前社長說 我們不接這案子了
Please do it a bit later.
請再等一下
Mr. Kurokawa?
黑川律師？
The first hearing is three days later.
三天後就是第一次公判了
I'll do something before that.
在那之前我會想辦法的
-Do something? -Anyway.
-想什麼辦法？ -總之
Let me stick to it until we can't.
請讓我堅持到最後一刻吧
Please.
拜託了
Mr. Kurokawa!
黑川律師
The kidnapper told us not to do anything!
綁架犯明說了要你什麼也別做
Haruto is in danger!
這可是關乎晴斗的性命啊
Why do you insist on doing this?
為什麼你還堅持這樣做？
I don't understand.
我實在無法理解
We're looking for witness information about a woman and a boy in Tokyo.
我們已經開始 在都內進行目擊情報搜索
Please rest so you can take action when necessary.
為了隨時能動身，請您先好好休息
Thank you, sir.
拜託你們了
You know…
我…
I was going to run away…
曾經想逃避母職
from being Haruto's mother.
拋下晴斗不管
Yes?
什麼？
At that time,
那時
I had been irritated by Haruto's naughty behavior.
我對晴斗的任性特別煩躁不耐
It was so tough to be a single mother
當個單親媽媽實在太辛苦了 剛好那時離婚的前夫
When I started working at Hoshundo
當時我剛開始在保駿堂工作
and aimed to be a lawyer…
想以律師為目標
Haruto's classmates said something to him.
托兒所的孩子似乎這樣跟晴斗說了
They said lawyers were the bad guys' friends.
說律師是壞蛋的同夥
And Haruto said he hated me.
於是他就說他討厭這樣的我
At that time, Haruto had a fever.
那段期間，某次晴斗剛好發燒…
Aren't lawyers the bad guys' friends?
律師是壞蛋的同夥吧？
Gosh, Haru.
真是的，小晴
We aren't the bad guys' friends.
律師不是壞蛋的同夥
A lawyer's job is to check whether the guy is really bad or not.
律師的工作是調查 所謂的壞蛋是否真的有做壞事
So, you're a hero?
所以是正義的夥伴囉？
We take the side of the truth, I think?
是真相的夥伴吧
For example, you whine to your mommy sometimes,
譬如小晴有時候也會對媽媽很任性
but it doesn't make you a bad boy, and you love your mommy, right?
但你並不是個壞孩子 而且最愛媽媽了，對吧？
Yeah.
對
And that's the truth.
這就是真相
After listening to Mr. Kurokawa,
聽了黑川律師的那番話
I understood something too.
我總算明白了
I want to stay with Haruto.
我想跟晴斗一起生活
I don't want to leave him.
不想跟他分開
And that…
那就是…
was the truth about me.
屬於我的真相
Yet, I…
結果卻…
Haruto.
晴斗
What should I do?
怎麼辦？
Two more people.
再追加兩人份
Hirayama.
平山
I'm Hoshundo Law Office's lawyer.
我是保駿堂法律事務所的律師
My name is Noboribetsu.
敝姓登別…
Ms. Wakura.
和倉律師
The whole office will look for Haruto today.
今天事務所全體總動員幫忙找晴斗
-Look for Haruto? -Yes.
-幫忙找晴斗？ -對
Isawa is looking for the members of the club
石和正在調查
Tarumae and Niijima joined.
跟樽前裕也及新島彰同社團的人
We're using the magazine that the woman brought here as our clue.
線索就是那名女子拿來的雜誌
Because of the murder,
由於這起殺人案
many on the Internet are talking about what they did back in college.
樽前與新島 大學時代的惡行也在網路瘋傳
Their names had not been reported in the past,
只是這之前的報導 並沒有報出真實姓名
but the woman knew their names.
但那名女子 卻知道是他們兩人所做的惡行
That means she was involved?
所以她是相關人士？
Judging by her age, she's probably related to one of the victims.
從年齡看來，應該是受害學生的親屬
This is what Kurokawa realized.
這是黑川注意到的
Besides the case,
不只是官司 他也絕對不會放棄晴斗的
Excuse me. Would someone go see Dr. Akiu?
不好意思 有人能幫我去秋保先生那裡一趟嗎？
-He has the result of the analysis I want. -Analysis?
-我拜託他做的分析結果出來了 -分析？
Yes. I think I'd better not step out of the office.
對，我還是別離開事務所比較好
I'll go for you, then.
由我去吧
Thank you.
拜託了
October 2. The idiot is making noise today too.
10月2日，那個混蛋今天也一樣吵
The home of the person who took the video is here
拍攝這影片的人住在這裡
and the police went to interview people who live in this area.
而警方問話的住宅是在這附近
All the residents said that they didn't hear the bass
每戶人家都說案發當天沒聽到貝斯聲
But they only said what they remembered.
但那都是憑記憶說的證詞
If the volume was the same as the tape's,
從影片分析出來的音量
the sound would at least travel to as far as this area.
至少也有傳到這附近
Okay.
我明白了 我會在這範圍內搜尋是否有人錄下
who recorded video or sound on the day of the murder.
可當作證據的影像或音檔
Have you found Ms. Kinosaki's son?
城崎小姐的兒子呢？
We're looking for clues now.
大家正在尋找線索
The pain of losing a family member in a case
在案件中失去家人的痛苦
I read the document about that case.
我看過那起案件的資料了
Your sister was a student in Touo University?
令妹也是東央大學的學生吧？
We have no time to talk about the past now.
現在不是說這些往事的時候
Thanks for waiting.
久等了
ONE DAY BEFORE FIRST HEARING
（距離第一次公判還有一天）
I'd like to ask about this article you wrote.
我想問問關於您以前寫過的這篇報導
Oh, this is pretty horrible.
這個啊，這相當慘烈呢
I had collected some materials,
當時我有進行採訪
but the gang rapist's dad pressured me.
卻被犯人們的親屬施壓
This is the part I would like to check with you.
我想確認的是這個部分
A STUDENT KILLED HERSELF BECAUSE OF THE SHOCK
（學生大受打擊，自殺身亡）
Do you know the name of the student who killed herself?
您知道因此事自殺的學生姓名嗎？
Excuse me.
不好意思
What are you filming with the camera?
請問您都在拍什麼呢？
It's my hobby.
這是我的興趣
Wild birds fly to this area,
這附近常有野鳥
so I keep the camera on the whole day every day.
所以我每天都從早拍攝到傍晚
Mr. Kurokawa, I found it!
黑川律師，找到了
-Haruto? -Oh, not him.
-找到小晴了嗎？ -不是的
It's a video with the sound of the bass on the day of the murder.
是案發當天犯案時刻 有錄到貝斯聲的影片
Oh, that.
什麼嘛
-What? Really? -Yes.
-什麼？真的嗎？ -是的
The camera at this house caught it.
就在這戶人家拍攝的影片裡
If it was heard here, no doubt the neighbors heard it too.
如果這裡聽得到 鄰居肯定也會聽到的
But I don't get why they all said they didn't hear it.
但我還不明白為什麼大家都說沒聽到
There must be a reason.
肯定有原因，調查之後就會知道了
Why did you not deny the possibility of it being a false charge?
黑川律師 你為什麼沒放棄冤罪的可能性？
Tarumae is clearly suspicious.
樽前明明就很可疑
It was strange that the circumstantial evidence was perfect.
讓我起疑的部分 是狀況證據實在是太齊全了
If he really was the murderer,
如果他真是犯人，未免也太不掩飾了
He didn't get rid of the gun and the shoes he wore to the warehouse.
無論是犯案時用的槍 或是在現場穿的鞋子
They were found at his home, and that's unnatural.
居然都放在家裡沒處理掉 實在太不自然了
Who killed Niijima then?
那麼殺害新島的是誰？
-Hello. Kurokawa speaking. -It's Arima.
我是黑川
about the people who bear a grudge towards Tarumae and Niijima.
包括跟樽前及新島有仇的人
Really? Even where Haru is?
真的嗎？ 那小晴的所在地也知道了嗎？
Sorry, there's construction work and I can't hear you.
抱歉，這裡在施工 太吵了，我聽不清楚
Construction?
施工？
Mr. Yuya shut himself in his room the whole day.
裕也少爺一直關在房間裡
But all the neighbors said they didn't hear the bass.
附近鄰居都說沒聽到貝斯聲
Mr. Kurokawa? What's the matter?
黑川律師，怎麼了嗎？
I see.
原來如此
Could it be…
說不定是…
-Mr. Kurokawa, don't go out! -That's right!
-黑川律師，你不能出門啊 -對喔
Anyway, I'll call Dr. Akiu first.
那個…總之要先聯絡秋保先生
-No… -Wait…
-不對… -等等…
-And Haru… -Calm down!
-還有小晴的事…還有… -冷靜，你先冷靜啊
Okay.
我明白了
Thank you.
萬事拜託了
The hostage's life is at risk.
這關乎人質的性命
Goodbye.
失陪了
The police is going there now with Kinosaki.
警方正在趕過去
They will definitely make it in time.
一定能趕上的
Your Honor, it's time to start the hearing.
審判長，開庭的時間到了
Well, we cannot get hold of the defense lawyer.
不，關於這個 我們一直聯絡不上辯護人
Sorry, we're late.
抱歉來遲了
Please start the hearing as scheduled.
請按原定計畫審理
December 26.
11月26日，今天也是 不但有人在施工，還有貝斯聲
I really wish the stupid boy were dead!
真希望那戶人家的蠢兒子趕快死一死
Idiot! You suck at it!
混蛋傢伙，彈得難聽死了…
Hey, how dare you say I'm an idiot, you jerk!
喂，你說誰蠢了？混蛋
Defendant, please don't speak.
被告，注意你的發言
You live opposite the defendant's house
您住在被告自宅對面
and you film it every time you hear him play the bass?
每當聽到貝斯聲都會拍影片存證吧？
Yes, I keep all of them as evidence of the noise he makes.
對，我全都有留下來 當成他噪音擾鄰的證據
On the day of the murder,
那麼案發當天 12月19日的下午兩點到三點呢？
I didn't film anything that day.
那天我沒拍
Because I didn't hear the sound of his bass.
因為我沒聽到貝斯聲
I see.
原來如此 剛才播放的影片也包含了施工的聲音
Was it also carried out on the day of the murder?
案發當天是否也有施工？
Yes. I think I heard the sound of the construction work.
對，我似乎有聽到施工聲
Did it sound like this?
是這種聲音嗎？
Yes, indeed. That's the sound.
沒錯，就是這樣的聲音
Okay. Thank you, ma'am.
我明白了，謝謝您
I've finished my questions.
以上是辯方的提問
Police.
我們是警察
I see.
這樣啊
You found me.
還是被找到了啊
Haruto!
晴斗
Mommy!
媽媽
Mrs. Yoriko Maruyama?
你是丸山依子吧？我們依綁架
and you're under arrest for kidnapping of minors.
未成年者現行犯罪名逮捕你
Please…
拜託了
Do me a favor.
我有個請求
Okay, I'll tell them at once.
明白了，我馬上轉達
Great!
太好了
What's the matter, defendant?
辯方，怎麼了嗎？
Nothing.
沒事
I'm sorry.
很抱歉
Now, please have a look at this.
那麼請先看這個資料
DEFENSE EVIDENCE NUMBER 48
（辯方第48號證據）
The house is 30 meter away from the defendant's
這是距離被告宅邸30公尺處的人家
and the video was taken by a camera set to observe wild birds.
所設置的野鳥觀測用相機影像
As you've heard, it's faint,
如剛才所聽到的，雖不明顯 但仍可聽到被告彈奏的貝斯聲
And this… was taken at the same time the murder was committed.
而這影片剛好 與案發當天犯案時刻相同
This is absurd.
不可能
The home of the witness just now is ten meters away from the defendant's.
剛才的證人住家 距離被告宅邸10公尺
It wasn't heard there. Why--
那麼近都沒聽到了，為什麼…
We're granted special permission to re-enact the video,
請看已獲得特別許可提出的 辯方第48號證據影片重現驗證
The expert witness, Dr. Akiu, will explain this.
由鑑定證人秋保副教授來進行說明
Dr. Akiu,
秋保教授
what is the reason that something like this happens?
為什麼會發生這種情況呢？
This can be explained by a certain phenomenon.
關於這點，經由某種現象便能說明
It's possible to re-enact it here.
也能在現場重現
Experience? Experience what?
體驗？體驗什麼？
Please stand there.
請檢察官站到那邊
Okay.
好了
Everyone, can you hear my voice?
各位，聽得到我的聲音嗎？
If you can, please raise your hand.
聽到請舉手
Can you hear my voice?
聽得到我的聲音嗎？聽到請舉手
Okay, let's continue.
那麼要繼續下去了
I'll ask again.
那麼再來一次 各位，聽得到我的聲音嗎？
Can you hear my voice?
聽得到我的聲音嗎？
If you can…
聽到請…
Public Prosecutor, could you hear my voice?
檢察官，有聽到我的聲音嗎？
I couldn't after some time.
不，中途開始就聽不到了
This phenomenon is caused by human auditory characteristics.
這是聽覺特性引發的現象
The human ear picks up sounds of higher frequencies
比起低頻率，人類的耳朵
more easily than lower frequencies.
更容易聽到高頻率的聲音
The lawyer was wearing a mask.
戴上口罩之後
This lowered the frequency of the sound of his voice
辯護人的聲音會更偏低頻
and we played a higher frequency sound with the speaker behind.
此時我打開了後方音響，發出高頻音
The sound from the speaker couldn't reach the panel of judges,
所以音響的聲音傳不到的法官側 能聽到辯護人的聲音
but the sound could reach the public prosecutor,
但在音響傳音範圍內的檢察官 就聽不到辯護人的聲音了
This phenomenon also occurred around the area of the defendant's house.
這現象也發生在被告宅邸附近
On the day of the murder,
案發當天，此位置正在施工
An asphalt cutter was used
使用了稱為道路切割機 會發出高頻噪音的機器
This is the area that the sound could travel.
這聲音的傳播範圍如下
And the sound of the bass played by the defendant
而被告彈奏的貝斯聲傳播範圍則如下
In the overlapping area, due to our auditory perception,
在兩個範圍重疊處 由於聽覺特性，會聽到高頻施工聲
Therefore, they couldn't hear the low-frequency sound of the bass.
因此就聽不到低頻的貝斯聲了
This is the reason
這就是案發當天
that the sound of the bass reached a house 30 meters away
距離30公尺處人家聽到貝斯聲
but residents of the houses nearer didn't hear it on the day of the murder.
而距離更近的鄰居卻沒聽到的原因
That's the end of the experiment.
以上就是驗證內容
CROSS EXAMINATION OF DEFENSE WITNESS
（辯護方詢問證人）
Mr. Usuta.
有珠田先生
As shown in the experiment,
如同剛才驗證
we can prove that the defendant was home at the time of the murder.
我們證明了案發犯案時刻
However,
只不過
this raises another problem.
這麼一來又有其他問題了
Yes?
是
The airgun used to kill the victim
用於犯案的空氣槍跟犯案現場的鞋子
must have been taken out by someone other than the defendant.
由並非被告的第三者帶了出去
And only very few people could do that.
而能做到這件事的人相當有限
Hey.
喂
Don't tell me…
難道…
Mr. Usuta, you started working at the defendant's home
有珠田先生 你從五年前開始在被告宅邸工作
Eight years ago,
而八年前，你跟離婚的前妻
and a daughter as well, right?
育有一女，對吧？
Your daughter, Ms. Yuki Maruyama…
令嬡，丸山由紀
ended her own life for some reason, while still in college.
就讀大學時因為某件事而自殺了吧？
Your Honor, the lawyer's question is not related to this case.
審判長
I confess.
我認罪
I killed Akira Niijima.
是我殺了新島彰
What?
什麼？
Hey, Usuta. Why did you do that, jerk?
喂，有珠田，你為什麼這麼做？
You should remember what you did back in college.
你還記得 你讀大學時做了些什麼事吧？
Mr. Usuta is the father of one of the victims.
有珠田先生就是受害者的父親
What?
什麼？
I…
我…
When my daughter was in middle school,
在女兒就讀國中時
my business failed and I got divorced.
由於事業失敗而離婚
I was told that…
某天我突然被告知
my daughter suddenly killed herself in her second year in university.
我就讀大學二年級的女兒自殺身亡了
My ex-wife, Yoriko, told me
我的前妻依子告訴我
that two students at her university,
我們的女兒是被同一所大學的學生
Akira Niijima and Yuya Tarumae, assaulted her.
新島彰與樽前裕也性侵
She was in agony because of that and killed herself.
痛苦不堪而走上絕路
I couldn't forgive them, no matter what.
我無論如何都無法原諒
That's why I…
所以我…
You went to work at Tarumae's house…
一邊在樽前家工作
and waited for a chance?
一邊等待時機，對吧？
Then, on that day…
而那天…
you used shopping as an excuse to go out to kill Niijima
藉口外出購物的你趁機殺害了新島
and asked your ex-wife, your accomplice, to buy the things.
請你的前妻 也就是共犯，代替你去買東西
Then you arranged everything
並且做了嫁禍給被告的掩飾工作
You chose Tarumae Property Agency's empty warehouse to kill him
你之所以選在 樽前物產擁有的廢棄倉庫犯案
because it was where the club gathered at that time.
是因為那就是當時 那個大學社團的聚集地吧？
Yes, you're right.
是的，沒錯
The place where my daughter was assaulted…
小女也是在那間倉庫遭到侵犯的
But in that case, why did you only kill Niijima
但是，既然如此 你為什麼只殺了新島
and put the blame on the defendant?
選擇讓被告背負罪名？
I found this out after I started working at Tarumae's house.
在樽前家工作後我才知道
The main culprit was Niijima,
新島才是主嫌
and Yuya…
而裕也…
he obeyed everything Niijima said
只是聽命於那傢伙的搖錢樹，所以…
Don't be ridiculous.
別開玩笑了，是你女兒自己要去死的
Defendant!
被告
-Be quiet. -What?
-請肅靜 -什麼？
This is what he is!
他就是這種人！
Mr. Kurokawa…
黑川律師
did you become a lawyer to help scums like him?
你是為了幫助這種男人 而成為律師的嗎？
The neighbors couldn't hear the sound of the bass.
鄰居沒聽到貝斯聲
It was really just a coincidence.
我知道單純只是偶然
I thought…
但我…
Yuki was helping us avenge her death in Heaven.
卻相信是死去的由紀在幫助我們復仇
And yet you…
結果你卻…
I am very sorry.
很抱歉
It is not hard to imagine…
不難想像…
the resentment you both feel.
兩位有多不甘心
If they had been properly punished by law…
如果那起大學案件使令嬡遭受的傷害
for what they did to your daughter…
能好好透過司法獲得公道…
maybe it wouldn't have driven you to a breaking point.
或許也不會把兩位逼入這個絕境了
But even so…
但是，即使如此…
he did not kill the victim.
他仍然沒殺死受害者
And…
這就是這起案件的真相
Exactly.
沒錯
I didn't kill him!
不是我殺的
Defendant!
被告
But I can't say that you aren't guilty.
即使如此，你也並非無罪
Your Honor.
審判長
Lay judges.
各位裁判員
For the above reasons…
基於上述理由
the defense lawyer claims that the defendant, Yuya Tarumae…
辯護人只針對被告樽前裕也…
on the charge of murder only…
殺人之公訴事實…
is innocent.
主張無罪
Haruto! Thank goodness you're okay!
晴斗，你沒事真是太好了
Mommy, the lady was very nice to me.
媽媽，那個阿姨很溫柔呢
Was she?
是嗎？
She kept saying sorry.
她一直跟我道歉
She said her daughter died because of some bad guys
說是因為她的小孩
Wait a minute!
請等一下
We have brought you all a lot of trouble.
真的給各位添麻煩了
We are really sorry.
真的非常抱歉
I cannot forgive you…
把孩子牽連進來
for getting my son involved.
簡直不可原諒
But…
但是，同樣為人父母
how you feel…
我對你們的心情…
No, you don't have to know.
你不需要明白
when someone killed their child.
孩子被殺死的父母的心情
Please…
請盡量灌注愛情
give him a lot of love.
養育你的孩子吧
Give him the love that we couldn't give our daughter.
連同我們沒能給女兒的份一起
Sure.
好
I will.
我會這麼做的
Goodbye, ma'am.
阿姨，拜拜
SUSPECT OF FATAL SHOOTING WAS FOUND INNOCENT
（品川區槍殺案，被告獲無罪判決）
Thank goodness we found Haruto unharmed.
順利找到晴斗，真是太好了
The guy was falsely charged of murder,
不過殺人案雖是冤罪
but he doesn't feel guilty at all, and I'm not happy about it.
被告卻毫無反省之意 真讓人難以釋懷
He violated the Firearm and Sword Control Law.
他免不了會被追究非法持有槍械罪
Also, the ladies he assaulted are going to sue him.
而且遭受暴行的女性們 似乎也重新提起告訴了
Of course, Mr. Beppu can't agree to defend him too.
所長也不可能再接相關辯護了吧
I'm afraid I have to say no.
我已經說不接了
Why?
為什麼？
Because he isn't falsely charged.
因為這次不是冤罪了
Blimey!
真是的
Why did you take the effort to come?
然後呢？你特地來做什麼？
I'd like to listen to the rest of the past.
我想聽聽那些往事
What was he like?
對方是怎樣的人？
The person that your sister…
跟秋保教授的妹妹…
The murderer that she was seeing?
交往的那名犯人嗎？
The reason that Mr. Kurokawa insists on doing this…
黑川律師會這麼執著
is something else.
有其他原因
What is the other reason?
什麼其他原因？
The murderer was…
因為犯人…
Mr. Kurokawa's childhood friend.
是黑川律師從小一起長大的死黨
His body build is very much like Kurokawa's current one.
他的身形大概跟現在的黑川差不多
CRIMINAL LAW JOURNAL
（《刑事法雜誌》）
I can't really remember this guy's face.
但我幾乎記不起這傢伙的臉了
THE DRAMA IS FICTITIOUS
（本劇純屬虛構）
It's the commonly-called Oume Casanova Murder Case.
被稱為青梅卡薩諾瓦殺人案
I didn't do it.
不是我做的
As a lawyer, he is branded as a failure.
陷入沒資格當律師的危機
You should take off the badge.
最好還是把你的律師徽章摘下
Maybe I'm not cut out to be a lawyer.
看來我或許還是不適合當律師啊
He risks his life to do an experiment to find out the truth.
為了找出真相而賭命實驗
Mr. Kurokawa!
黑川律師
I'll investigate thoroughly…
我會徹底調查…
If you think you can't win, I'll look for someone more skillful.
調查後如果沒勝算 我會找更厲害的律師來
His will?
遺囑？
She killed him for his money?
她為了財產而痛下殺手嗎？
I wonder what I'm trying to investigate.
我現在到底是打算調查什麼呢？
Your life as a lawyer is really over.
你的律師生涯真的就要結束了
Marina, I want you to be saved!
我希望你能獲得救贖